here in America our bipartisan system is
almost split the country down the middle
however in Hawaii one party is fighting
for survival
take a look Hawaii with only about 25%
white people this Pina Colada so
paradise could be the political crystal
ball for the rest of the US so how does
the future look except for of course a
lot of fat guys playing ukuleles well
very good if you're a Democrat in fact
why is basically a one-party system at
the state level Democrats outnumber
Republicans 76 to 5 at the federal level
it's all Democrats plus a Democratic
governor there's even a Democratic
former president who was born here
allegedly Republicans resistant what are
their strongest voices is state
representative and Tommy Bahama
enthusiast Bob McDermott how important
is it for you to grow the Republican
Party here in Hawaii
it's important and to do it Bob's
relying on all the Republican Party's
old favorites gay marriage when you have
same-sex marriage the homosexuals want
this talk to the kids that this is a
healthy wholesome moral equivalent of
male/female reproduction
you know Margaret Sanger she started
Planned Parenthood to eliminate black
kids well I don't know about that with
non-white fighters I'm married to a
Samoan I have a beautiful wife and
beautiful multiracial kids so when I put
that mailer out people living at say
well he must be okay seems reasonable to
me
I keep a picture of my black friend in
my wallet
I feel like why GOP needs a bit of an
update luckily there's a young moderate
voice in Honolulu meet state
representative Beth Fukumoto she joined
the Republican Party and rose quickly to
a leadership post what made you become a
Republican Republicans are doing a
terrible job with women they're not
reaching out to minorities they need a
diversity they needed a new voice you're
very impressive the Republicans must be
really happy to have you
well actually I am a Democrat now Jeff
Beck was actually drummed out of the
Hawaii Republican Party and the person
who led the charge what Bob got elected
all these women at us what the hell the
protest was called but she went and
spoke at it yeah what was that little
get-together cold oh yeah the woman's
match millions of women here it is tough
to remember she got up and spoke and
took a big old dump on Trump
[Music]
the feminazis of feminazi seven odd
she's got out there and she went out
there with it they felt like I was
attacking the president and we to some
extent I was yeah and there's nothing
wrong with that there shouldn't be
anything that's what democracy is all
about but you Republic that's where the
backlash came in things came to a boil
on the floor of a wise House of
Representatives Bob came around desk
stood in front of me and just started
shouting I told her do her job and then
I said start acting like a
Republican are you a good actor how does
one act like a Republican you
have principles when you follow through
on it but didn't bet speak out because
Trump crossed a line with her what line
it was like two days after the
inauguration you just got in to just say
well somebody shouldn't speak out of
turn because they should be following
just their party it's silly nobody wants
that
so Beth switched parties but she's not
the only one
in fact since 2015 nearly one-quarter of
Republican Millennials in the US have
defected to the Democrats now I'm not a
political strategist but seems like
that's not a good stat for people like
Bob so I asked him to name one more key
issue that he thinks could bring
Republicans back his answer why sex
education program called pono choices in
particular the fact that in textbooks
the anus was defined as a genital why we
don't kids it's a sexual reproductive
organ a reproductive organ yes the
yes reproductive yeah no I'm
saying it's not long with you if they're
teaching that you have to start that
right now he's good stalk google hook on
Google what I know many times I trust me
I've done some research oh no choice
I hope you invented the word mangina
angina yeah that's because of the pono
choices no you did know I've been using
the word mangina since the turn of the
century
okay well that's when you suck your dick
and balls between your legs and you
close your legs up so it looks like you
have a vagina and you go I'm a girl on
the go that's see that's a different
definition you've never done that why
would I
now crew you've all done that right yeah
everyone done that
so as the Sun set on my time in Hawaii
I started to realize that having two
choices is better than one sure people
like Bob and Trump say crazy for
now it even gets them elected but the
numbers don't lie if they keep it up
we'll end up in an ocean of Democrats
just like away and no matter who you
agree with a one-party system is not
what democracy is all about
[Music]